<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">ASL Pocket Dictionary</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_search_by_word">SearchByWord</string>
    <string name="title_activity_learn_more_asl">LearnMoreASL</string>
    <string name="title_activity_training_game">TrainingGame</string>
    <string name="menu_settings" />
    <string name="title_activity_result" />
    <string name="str_next">Next</string>
    <string name="title_activity_search_by_category">SearchByCategory</string>

    <string-array name="fun_facts">
        <item> "Although Britain and the US share a spoken language, their sign languages have grown up separately. American Sign Language (ASL), also used in much of Canada, is heavily influenced by French Sign Language. British Sign Language (BSL) is similar to Australian Sign Language (AusLan)."</item>
        <item> "In ASL, finger-spelling requires only one hand. In British Sign Language (BSL), letters are formed using both hands (with the exception of ‘C’). Both systems have advantages, BSL letters being easier to learn as they are more systematic and many resemble their written counterparts."</item>
        <item> "Sign languages convey meaning through the positioning and expression of various parts of the body, including facial expressions, lip patterns and upper body and head movement."</item>
        <item>"Sign languages can convey ideas on any subject. Poetry is written in sign languages, and jokes are told all the time! Despite their complexity, they can be easier to learn than spoken languages, as signs often bear a closer resemblance to the ideas they signify than words can."</item>
        <item>"The grammar of British Sign Language (BSL) and also of ASL are very different to those of spoken English. Word (sign) order is altered, some words such as ‘the’ are not used, and others such as orange (the fruit) and orange (the color) have distinct signs. Signed English is a system which applies ASL or BSL signs to the grammar of spoken English."</item>
        <item>"Pidgin Signed English (PSE) is basically ASL signed in English order. Many deaf children, who sign, with hearing parents use PSE because ASL word order is different from English word order. "</item>
        <item>"Gallaudet University was the first college for the deaf in America and was named after Thomas Hopkins Gallaudet. It is a private and very expensive college which hearing people can attend BUT deaf persons get first ‘pick.’"</item>
        <item>"Other than the US, ASL is used often in Canada as well. Canada does not have an official sign language of its own, although there is a specific “Quebec Sign Language” which is more or less confined in its use to Quebec itself. Many Deaf Canadians use ASL."</item>
        <item>"Hearing-Impaired people may not like to call themselves ‘deaf’, and would often like to recover their hearing, but the term ‘Deaf’ (with a capital ‘D’) is applied to people who are proud of their culture and languages. They may well have been deaf since birth and gone to a school for deaf children. Some people would include groups such as hearing children of deaf parents under the term Deaf."</item>
        <item>"Sign languages can and are learnt by people of all ages, including pre-school children. If someone has a physical disability which makes it difficult for them to sign conventionally, it is usually easy for them to adapt the language as necessary. Sign languages can be adapted in many ways and are even being used by deaf-blind people in addition to the deal-blind manual, a system of letters traced on a hand."</item>
        <item>"For purpose of conversing using sign language, deaf people have a ‘sign name.”"</item>
        <item>"The National Association of Deaf (NAD) is the nation’s premier civil rights organization of, by and for deaf and hard of hearing individuals in the US. Established in 1880, NAD was founded in Cincinnati, OH. Currently, NAD is located at Silver Spring, MD."</item>
        <item>"Different countries have different sign languages. Sign languages, like spoken languages, developed naturally out of groups of people interacting with each other."</item>
        <item>"Given a few generations, improvised gestures can evolve into a full language in sign language. "</item>
        <item>"Sign languages does not represent spoken language. Because sign languages develop within deaf communities, they can be independent of the surrounding spoken language. ASL is quite different from British Sign Language (BSL), despite the fact that English is the spoken language of both countries."</item>
        <item>"Sign languages have their own grammar. There are rules for well-formed sentences in sign languages. For example, sign languages uses the space in front of the signer to show who did what to whom by pointing. Another rule is that a well-formed question must have the right kind of eyebrow position. Eyebrows should be down for a who-what-where-when-why question, and up for a yes/no question. If you use the rules wrong, or inconsistently, you will have a “foreign” accent!"</item>
        <item>"Children acquire sign language in the same way they acquire spoken language. The stages of sign language acquisition are the same as those for spoken language."</item>
        <item>"Brain damage affects sign language in the same way it affects spoken language. When fluent signers have a stroke or brain injury, they may lose the ability to sign, but not to make imitative or non-sign gestures. They may be able to produce signs, but not put them in the correct grammatical configurations. They may be able to produce sentences, but with the signs formed incorrectly, creating a strange accent. They may be able to sign quickly and easily, but without making any sense."</item>
        <item>"Sign language is a visual language. Sign language is just like spoken language in many ways, but it’s also different. Sign can be very straightforward and formal, but it can also take full advantage of its visual nature for expressive or artistic effect. "</item>
        <item>"Those who were born completely deaf and only learnt sign language will think in sign language. However, those who were born completely deaf but learn to speak through vocal training will occasionally think not only in the particular sign language that they know, but also will sometimes think in the vocal language they learned, with their brains coming up with how the vocal languages sounds."</item>
        <item>"ASL resembles Chinese in form more than it does English in terms of a single gesture often represent a phrase or whole idea, rather than a single word. "</item>
        <item>"Our brains treat sign language exactly as it treats spoken language, even using the exact same part of the brain to process it. It uses the same portion of the left hemisphere to process sign languages as it does for vocal language in the hearing."</item>
        <item>"If you take a deaf person and make them grip something hard with their hands while asking them to memorize a list of words, this has the same disruptive effect as making a hearing person repeat some nonsense phrase such as “Bob and Bill” during memorization tasks."</item>
        <item>"While there are many standardized sign languages used, unlike spoken languages, there are also literally thousands of simple sign “languages” used among family units. This is  particularly the case with non-deaf parents that have a deaf child. They will often develop numerous home signs and some sort of structured system of using the signs to communicate."</item>
        <item>"Ever wondered how the deaf wake themselves up in the morning? The most foolproof method, outside of someone just coming to wake you up, is a very strong vibrating  accessory attached to a special alarm clock. The attachment asthenia generally placed under the pillow or on the bed near the person. Another common method is an alarm clock that has a bright light attached that points at the sleeper. When the alarm goes off, it flashes brightly on and off. "</item>
        <item>"Similar to spoken language, sign languages have accents. Typically these manifest themselves in small variations in how one does a gesture or the like. "</item>
        <item>"Deaf people can typically readily identify those deaf people who began signing later in life by their “late learner” accent."</item>
        <item>"One of the marks of a “southern” ASL accent is that southern signers sign much slower than northern signers, essentially mimicking the southern drawl in sign."</item>
        <item>"Along with differing accents, there are numerous dialects, among various deaf communities, that technically use the same sign language."</item>
        <item>"Deaf people typically clap by striking their hands together only when surrounded by hearing people. Otherwise, they use the more expressive motion of raising their hands and twisting their wrists rapidly to “clap.”"</item>
        <item>"The earliest record of sign language being used dates all the way back to the fifth century B.C., in Plato’s Cratylus, where Socrates states: “If we hadn’t a voice or a tongue, and wanted to express things to one another, wouldn’t we try to make signs by moving our hands, head, and the rest of our body, just as dumb people do at present?”"</item>
        <item>"Roughly one person out of every one thousand born is born completely deaf."</item>
        <item>"It is quite common for deaf people, when they are dreaming, to not only communicate in their dreams using sign language, but also to communicate telepathically and sometimes even verbally even though they may not know how to speak verbally in the waking world."</item>
        <item>"Research has shown that deaf people are able to learn a sign language, such as ASL, significantly faster than the non-deaf learn spoken language. "</item>
        <item>"The critical age for learning language is around 21 to 36 months old.  During this period, much of the cognitive infrastructure in a person’s brain is developed and it is thought, much of it is developed as a result of learning language."</item>
        <item>"Sign Languages are not often written due to the incredibly complexity of trying to replicate the non-sequential nature of signing. The non-sequential nature of sign languages allows for faster and more detailed communication, but has the drawback of being ridiculously hard to put into print, though attempts have been made."</item>
        <item>"Sign Language is not just an alphabet where you have to sign each letter of the word you are trying to communicate. Sign Language is a complete language with a sign representing the majority of words found in written English. It's rarely required to spell a word because no sign exist."</item>
        <item>"Babies can communicate physically 6 en dash 8 months prior to communicating verbally."</item>
        <item>"American Sign Language (ASL) is the third most widely used language in the U.S., after English and Spanish."</item>
        <item>"A form of ASL has been used in the U.S. for over two hundred years."</item>
        <item>"Many people with hearing impairments communicate by using ASL, which combines hand signs, gestures, and facial expressions to create words and sentences. As many as 500,000 people in the U.S. communicate using ASL."</item>
        <item>"Different countries have different sign languages. ASL also has regional and dialectal differences depending on age, gender, culture, and more. There are thousands of different sign languages, approximately 6,000."</item>
        <item>"Modern-day ASL didn't come from England. It came from France, which is why French Sign Language is similar to American Sign Language. England has its own version of signed language which is very different from ASL, known as Modern British Sign Language."</item>
        <item>"Sign languages have their own grammar and syntax."</item>
        <item>"People acquire sign language in the same way they acquire spoken languages."</item>
        <item>"One sign in sign language can have multiple meanings."</item>
        <item>"Thomas Edison was a hearing impaired inventor who filed thousands of patents for his inventions."</item>
        <item>"Beethoven was a famous German composer and pianist who was also hearing impaired."</item>
        <item>"Alexander Graham Bell, inventor of the telephone, helped advance communication for the hearing impaired."</item>
        <item>"ASL is considered a foreign language."</item>
        <item>"Deaf History Month is observed from March 13th to April 15th every year."</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_basic_training_game">BasicTrainingGameActivity</string>

    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>

</resources>
